ANTI-BACTERIAL SPRAY
（殺菌噴霧）
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Ken.
研先生
I may be able to kill the bacteria that live in my body if I drink this.
只要喝下這個 或許就能殺死我體內的菌了
Wait a minute. I don't think so.
等等，這可說不準啊
-Let me try. -Wait!
-我要試試看 -等等，叫你等等啊
Wait a minute.
等等
What are you doing?
你們在做什麼？
Tsugaru.
津輕小姐
I'm sorry for what I've done.
至今很抱歉
I will kill the bacteria so that I can live in the human world.
為了在人類世界活下去 我要喝下這個，殺死菌類
Wait!
等等，不是的
That's not what I meant.
不是這樣的
I put you on the radio.
讓你上廣播的是我
I encouraged you to go on the radio.
是我讓你上廣播節目的
I thought Tsugaru would come to her senses
我以為只要研先生引發意外 津輕小姐就會比較冷靜
So she wouldn't love you.
就不會戀愛了
That's why I met Amakusa.
所以我才親自去找天草先生
I told him that you were a monster.
說你是怪物，引發他的興趣
I wished that
今天會變這樣
you would cause trouble like today.
也是因為我潛意識裡 希望這樣的事發生
Ken.
研先生
It's me…
不是人類的…
who is not human.
是我才對
I loved Tsugaru before you fell in love with her.
我比研先生你更早愛上津輕小姐
But…
但是…
I always give her a hard time.
我卻總是讓心愛的人痛苦
Tsugaru is suffering because of me.
現在也在折磨著津輕小姐
This is who I am.
這就是我的真面目
ASK AMAKUSA!
（問問天草吧）
Can't you get hold of the monster yet?
-還沒連絡上怪物嗎？ -沒辦法，他不接電話
AMAKUSA
（天草來電）
At first, I just wanted to protect Tsugaru.
起初我是為了保護津輕小姐
Then I came to like Ken.
但我慢慢地也喜歡上了研先生
I am not lying.
這不是謊言
The more I wanted to help Ken,
但我越是想幫助研先生
the more I wanted to sully your pure heart.
越想玷汙研先生那純潔的心
I wanted to reveal his true character, that of a monster.
想要揭穿他身為怪物的本性
Every human…
人類這種生物
lives with contradictions.
都是懷抱著矛盾在過活的
Contradictions?
矛盾？
We live knowing that we can't realize what we wish.
大家明明都想這樣做
I can't live with a pure heart like Ken.
我沒辦法像研先生一樣純潔地活下去
I live with poison that I can't get rid of.
我懷抱著無法消失的惡毒之心在活著
I envy you, Ken.
研先生真的很厲害
You don't have to hate yourself.
所以你不需要痛恨自己
You should hate me instead.
要恨的話就恨我吧
I was bad. I put you in a corner.
因為一切都是我做的 是我把研先生逼到絕境的
Please.
拜託你了
You should hate me.
請你恨我吧
Hello. This is Inaniwa.
你好，我是稻庭
Hello, Mr. Inaniwa.
你好，是稻庭先生嗎？
I am Junpei Amakusa, a radio personality.
我是廣播局的天草純平
Is Ken Fukashi home?
請問府上的深志研先生回來了嗎？
Yes. Just a moment, please.
這…請等一下
Hey.
喂
Amakusa wants to talk to you…
天草先生打電話來了
Ken.
說要找研先生
-Hang up. -What?
-幫我掛斷吧 -什麼？
-It was no use. -Huh?
-沒辦法
He hung up.
被掛斷了
He seems to be home. I'll go see him.
-但他好像在，我去看看 -去了又能怎樣？
I don't know yet.
我也不知道
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好了 -怎麼了？
A lot of the people who came to see the public show
當時在公開廣播現場的幾名觀眾
Are they having the same symptoms as Tokachi?
跟十勝先生是相同狀況嗎？
I don't know.
還不清楚
It looked like he was spreading something.
這麼說來，他好像噴散了什麼出來啊
TOKYO MUSASHI BROADCASTING
（東京武藏廣播局）
Oh no.
這下糟糕了
What happened during the radio show?
廣播時到底發生什麼事了？
Everyone is worried about Ken.
大家都很擔心研先生呢
Nothing.
沒事
Thanks to Seiya, I came to my senses.
多虧了稻庭前輩，我總算覺醒了
Let me tell you the truth.
我要和大家說出事情的真相
What are you talking about?
你在胡說什麼啊，研先生？
It's not only humans who live with contradictions.
懷抱矛盾的不只是人類
I, a monster, also live with contradictions.
身為怪物的我也懷抱著矛盾
I wanted people to understand me,
雖然希望別人能了解我
although I was hiding who I really was.
卻隱藏著真正的自己
Seiya told us the truth.
稻庭前輩跟我說出了真相
So, I shall tell you the truth.
我也要說出真相
I am a monster.
我是怪物
Hey, Ken. What are you talking about since this morning?
研，你一早就在胡說什麼啊？
What I said on the radio was all true.
在廣播說的話全部都是真的
True?
都是真的？
I died 120 years ago
120年前，我曾死過一次
and my father, who was a doctor of medicine,
是身為醫學博士的父親 讓我死而復生的
Huh?
什麼？
Amakusa, what are you talking about?
天草，你在胡說什麼啊？
True?
-實話？ -所以…
and had lived alone in the forest since then.
在森林裡獨自活了120年
It's true.
這都是真的
Boss.
當家
Is he serious?
這是認真說的嗎？
Ken is serious.
研先生親口說了，這是認真的
It's true.
這是真的，他說的都是實話
Now is not a good time to joke around.
別再這種時候開玩笑了吧
I didn't believe him in the beginning.
我一開始也不相信啊
Are you serious?
你是認真的嗎？
Professor Tsurumaru guarantees it.
鶴丸教授也是這樣說的
Is he really a monster?
所以那傢伙是真正的怪物？
Monster?
要說是怪物…
Is he really spreading poison?
也就是說，他真的會噴散毒素？
It's not poison. He releases bacteria.
不是毒素，好像是菌類
Is that something like Bifidobacterium?
是像比菲德氏菌之類的嗎？
Tsugaru.
津輕小姐
Will you explain to them?
能請你告訴他們嗎？
Please.
拜託你了
Ken's body carries some kinds of bacteria.
研先生的體內有某種菌類
Some bacteria
那種菌當中有會傳染給人
So, I put him on the radio and tried to show it in public.
所以我才故意讓研先生上節目 想讓人們看看這事實
I wanted it to happen.
我就是想看到這情況
That's why Ken went on the radio and released bacteria.
所以研先生…
Was I infected by his virus?
所以我感染了那些菌類？
-Yes. -That's disgusting.
-沒錯 -好噁
Don't run away.
別逃啊
But I was cured, right?
我…已經治好了吧？
The doctor said I recovered.
是醫生說的，我才會出院的
Professor Tsurumaru made a specific medicine
是鶴丸教授做的特效藥
-and I gave it to you secretly. -Secretly?
-我們餵十勝先生偷偷喝了藥 -偷偷餵藥？
Why didn't Professor tell anyone?
為何都沒說？
Because no one would believe him.
說了也不會有人相信啊
Are you kidding me?
別開玩笑了，這些菌類
We could have been infected by his virus.
很可能會傳染給觀眾啊
It's possible. I will check.
這可能性很大，我馬上調查
Wait.
等等
We should call the police first.
在那之前先通報警察吧
We should tell the police that we knew nothing.
我們什麼都不知道 所以應該要報警才對
-Please wait. -Amakusa,
-請等一下 -天草
can you be responsible for this?
難道你能扛這責任嗎？
Look at this picture.
那個…這張照片…
SPORES COMING OUT OF FRANKEN? THIS IS CRAZY
（怪人體外長出孢子？太扯了吧）
Is this when you released bacteria?
這就是那些菌嗎？ 會從研先生體內噴散的菌
Yes.
對
I shouldn't touch people.
我…沒辦法觸碰人類
I shouldn't get upset or sad.
我不能生氣，也不能嘆息
If I do, I will release bad bacteria.
因為這樣就會跑出壞菌
I'm sorry for not telling you this.
很抱歉，隱瞞各位到現在
I am a monster.
我是個怪物
What did you think?
到底是怎樣？
-Say something. -Be quiet.
-你們說些什麼啊？ -你先閉嘴
Don't you think it's creepy?
感覺很噁心吧？
Are you scared to be close to Ken?
很怕研先生在身邊吧？
Shut up.
-給我閉嘴 -我不這麼想
Such half-hearted attitude put Ken into a corner.
這種半瓶水的體貼 只會把研先生逼入絕境的
You should be honest about your feelings.
再老實一點不就好了？
Do you think it's okay to hurt Ken?
就算如此，就能傷害研先生嗎？
Is that how you become honest?
這才是你的目的嗎？
You told Ken to do as he wanted, but actually, you disturbed him.
你一邊說要讓研自由 一邊故意扯他後腿？
-That's right. -I went on the radio,
-沒錯 -我會去上廣播
not because Seiya told me to.
不是稻庭前輩的錯
I did it because I wanted to.
是我自己想上才去上的
-You don't have to say that. -I thought…
-這種話就不用說了 -我認為在廣播
no one would think that I was a monster
只要我說自己是怪物
if I said it on the radio.
誰都不會認真覺得我是怪物
So, I pretended to be a monster.
-所以我才裝成怪物的樣子 -已經夠了
-You don't have to make up a lie. -It's not a lie.
-不用說這種謊言了！ -這不是謊言
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
I am like you.
我也有這樣的一面
I would do anything
只要是為了跟津輕小姐在一起
if it meant I could be with Tsugaru.
不管什麼事我都願意做
That's who I really am.
那就是我的真面目
Give me a break.
開什麼玩笑…
Why don't you get mad at me?
對我生氣啊！
If you are a monster, get mad at me like a monster.
既然是怪物的話 就像怪物一樣對我生氣啊！
I can't.
我辦不到
I also have a contradiction.
我也有矛盾之處
Even if you think I should get mad at you,
明明就應該對稻庭前輩生氣
I can't.
我卻無法生氣
Even if you think I should hate you,
如果一定要憎恨稻庭前輩的話
I…
因為我…
I like you so much.
最喜歡稻庭前輩了
I appreciate what you did.
直到現在，我還是很感謝你
This is why…
就是這種地方
you are bad.
研先生你最沒用的地方
This is what I don't like about you.
我最討厭研先生你這種地方了
Okay. Let's get to work.
好，回去工作吧
Are we going to work?
什麼？還要工作嗎？
Yes, of course.
當然
Ken. Let's get to work.
研先生，你也一樣
Me?
我也一樣嗎？
Yes, of course.
當然囉
-Let's work. -Okay.
-好了，快回去工作吧 -好
Don't worry about Seiya.
那傢伙的事就不用擔心了
Are you all right?
還好嗎？
You should leave me alone in a situation like this.
這種時候應該要讓我自己靜一靜吧
I'm like your father.
跟你父親很像
Just like you.
他跟你一樣
-I'm not like him. -Yes, you are.
-我跟那個人才不像呢 -很像的
Boss picked me up in town
我在街上被社長叫住
and brought me here.
剛來到這個家的時候
I saw you and Boss didn't get along well.
你跟社長裝得感情很不好的樣子
It made it easier for me to stay.
讓待在這裡的我輕鬆多了
That wasn't for you.
那可不是為了室園小姐你啊
Even so,
就算你不是那樣
that's how nice you are to people.
但這就是你溫柔的地方
You unconsciously showed me
或許你完全沒意識到
I could do as I wanted.
但是你跟我說，我可以自由地做自己
You were nice to me.
你對我很溫柔
I know…
我是很清楚的
that's how you are.
你的這一面
I know you are not perfect.
不是完美人類的地方
You are awkward when it comes to love.
不擅長戀愛的地方
You don't have a good eye for women.
還有沒看女人的眼光的地方
Murozono.
室園小姐…
Call me Mikoto.
都這時候了，叫我“美琴”啊
Do you think…
我能像以前一樣
you can have the same attitude with Ken as before?
和研先生相處嗎？
Will you be the same with him?
他會願意嗎？
Yes. If you ask me to be.
如果是你拜託的，我會請他幫忙的
Please.
拜託了
Okay.
我知道了
You can count on me.
包在我身上
It's hard to guess what he thinks since he was a child.
從以前我就時常會不懂 那傢伙在想什麼
When he was small,
那傢伙小時候
his mother went to hospital because of a heart disease.
母親因心臟病住院時
He went to the hospital every day and made her smile.
那傢伙每天都去醫院拼命逗母親笑
But he stole candy at the shop in the neighborhood
明明是這樣 他卻在附近店家偷了零食
and brought them to his mom.
帶去探望母親
He thought that his mom would be back from the hospital sooner
他似乎以為只要被母親發現 讓母親擔心
if she found out and worried about him.
母親就會趕快出院了
His mom cried
所以
and he apologized when she found out what he had done.
知道這件事的母親一邊哭著一邊道歉
But she didn't come back.
然後…母親就這樣不回來了
No.
不…
He got depressed so much.
那傢伙因為這樣很沮喪
He blamed himself although he was a child.
雖然是小孩，卻不停地責怪自己
It would have been better if he could cry.
要是當時他能像剛才那樣 放聲大哭就好了
But I cried slovenly at her funeral.
喪禮那時，我很不爭氣地哭了
So, he couldn't cry.
那傢伙一定是死撐著不哭
I think…
津輕小姐的事也是
he was worrying about you, seriously.
那傢伙一定也是認真地在為你擔心的
I know.
我知道
So…
所以…
I feel sorry for him.
對於稻庭前輩，我覺得很過意不去
I put Seiya in a corner.
把稻庭前輩逼到絕境的是我
I think…
我一直沒有
I didn't try to understand Ken.
真正理解深志先生
I tried to see only what I liked about him.
只看著自己喜歡的部分
I think Seiya is great.
前輩真的很厲害
He brought Ken here.
把深志先生帶來這裡
He tried to accept Ken as he really was.
還試著要接受深志先生的一切
It's wonderful.
真的很厲害
I…
我…
I am ashamed of myself.
覺得自己很丟臉
Thanks.
謝謝
But don't blame yourself.
但是，津輕小姐不用這麼自責
Have some tea.
-請用 -謝謝
It's not anyone's fault.
這不是誰的錯
It's hard to understand people.
人與人要彼此理解 本來就不是件簡單的事
This is an even harder situation.
再加上…沒想到天底下會有這種事
Tsugaru. You didn't sleep at all.
津輕小姐，你完全沒睡
Get some rest.
稍微去休息一下吧
Thank you.
謝謝
How is the radio show?
廣播那邊沒問題吧？
I guess people are making a big fuss.
似乎引發了很大的騷動啊
FUGAKU UNIVERSITY
（國立富嶽大學）
-Let's prepare more samples. -Okay.
-增加一些樣本吧 -是
Come in.
好
He is not here.
他沒來這裡
I need your help.
不，我是來找教授您商量的
Yes?
-有什麼事嗎？ -不好意思
I am responsible for what's happening right now.
這次的事都是我的責任
Is there anyone who was infected?
有受害者出現嗎？
The company decided to report it to the police.
廣播局正在考慮要不要通報警察
-Please wait. -Amakusa.
-請等一下 -天草
Can you be responsible for this?
難道你能扛這責任嗎？
Who is responsible for the radio?
廣播要怎麼負責？
For the radio?
怎麼負責？
This happened on our radio show. Are you going to leave it to the police?
明明就是我們廣播惹出的事 卻要交給警方辦嗎？
It's a crime spreading poison.
散佈毒素是犯罪吧
It's not poison, it's bacteria.
那又不是毒，那是菌啊
-It's the same. -No, it's not.
-一樣啊 -才不一樣呢
If he released bacteria, it's a big issue.
要是他真的散佈了菌的胞子 那可是很驚人的啊
It's a big fact.
是非常驚人的事實
What are you trying to say?
你到底想說什麼？
Don't you think that we should verify it on the radio?
我們不用在廣播驗證嗎？
Verify?
驗證？
Many listeners want to know what had happened on the show.
我想一定有很多聽眾在煩惱著 廣播當天發生的事
Don't you think that we should reply to them?
對於這件事，我們難道不用回答嗎？
What do you want me to do?
所以你想要我怎麼做？
I need your help.
希望您能幫忙
I want to let the public know the facts about Ken on the radio.
我們想在廣播上公開研先生的事
Huh?
什麼？
-Put it here. -Okay.
-那就放這裡吧 -是
What happened?
-怎麼了？ -沒事吧？研，別擔心
Don't get upset.
-請冷靜下來 -沒事的
Idiot! Calm down.
混帳東西！你們才給我冷靜呢
Boss, you got upset the most.
社長你明明就最怕
-Help him tidy up. -Give me a hand.
-幫忙整理吧 -你來幫我
-Sure. -Hold this.
-好 -幫我拿一下
It's all right.
沒事的
I got a fright.
嚇我一跳
Ken.
研先生
Professor Tsurumaru wants to see you.
鶴丸教授希望研先生你來一趟
Okay.
好的
-Can we go? -Okay.
-可以嗎？ -嗯
Is that Franken?
那是怪人嗎？
Amakusa!
天草先生…
What is this all about?
教授，這是怎麼回事？
He wants to talk to you.
只是要聊一聊而已
I am responsible for what had happened.
這次的事，是我的責任
I put Ken in a corner.
把研先生逼到絕境
I'm sorry.
真的很抱歉
No. It's not your fault.
不…這不是天草先生的錯
Some of the people who attended the live show
公開廣播當天的觀眾
became sick and went to the hospital.
有好幾位都說身體不舒服而送醫了
They are not in serious condition.
但大家都是輕傷
I confirmed that all of them went home without any problem.
調查之後發現全部傷患 都平安回家了
Please don't worry.
這件事不用擔心
But…
但是…
they think you are suspicious.
大家都在懷疑研先生
The radio station is going to report it to the police.
廣播局似乎會通報警察
What?
什麼？
I won't let them do such a thing.
我不會讓這種事發生的
Will you go on the radio and tell us the truth instead?
相對地，能請你上廣播 告訴大家實情嗎？
Do you want him to go on the radio again?
又要讓他上廣播嗎？
It's for Ken. I think it's better than to hide.
這是為了研先生 我想應該比逃避還好
What's good about it?
哪裡好了？
The media will chase you if you try to hide.
若是一直逃避，只會讓媒體追打而已
You did do something to Tokachi.
發生在十勝先生身上的事也是事實
If you don't explain anything, they will regard everything as fact.
這樣下去，流言蜚語 都會被傳成事實的
I want Ken to tell what he thinks is true
與其那樣，還是請研先生上廣播節目
on the radio.
告訴大家真相
I think
若今後還想跟人們一起過活 只能這樣做
Ken.
研先生
I want you to trust me one more time.
請你再相信我一次
If we know that he is a monster and let him talk on the show,
明知他是怪物還讓他上節目
the listeners may think that we are an accomplice.
一個不小心 我們節目會被當成共犯的
-We already are an accomplice. -What?
-這樣說的話，已經是共犯了啊 -什麼？
-That makes sense.
-不，或許真的行得通啊
Let him explain what had happened
讓他親口說出真相
so that we can say that we didn't know anything.
強調我們什麼都不知道
We didn't believe that he was a real monster.
我們沒相信他真的是怪物
We had no idea that he was such a strange man.
也沒想過他是那樣的怪人
We had never imagined that he would spread poison.
更不會想到他還會散播毒素
We should emphasize that we were deceived by him.
強調我們也是被他騙的
I'm not trying to do such a thing.
阿牛
You didn't believe what he said.
天草先生也不相信吧？
PARADISE HEAVEN
（天國廣播單元）
-Okay. Go for it. -Huh?
-好，就這麼做吧 -什麼？
It will be newsworthy and will have a high listener rating.
能引發話題，也能得到收聽率
I will never go on the show with such a man.
我可不要，才不要和他一起上節目呢
You do it by yourself, Amakusa.
天草先生你自己加油吧
Amakusa. Find the monster and drag him to the show.
天草，無論如何都要找到怪物 把他拉上廣播來
You can't fool me.
我們不會被騙的
You want him to go on the show just for yourself.
你…
Ken. He is like me.
研先生，這個人跟我一樣
People who want to help others actually want to help themselves.
說想要幫助別人的人 通常都是只想被幫助的人
He wants you to go on the radio for his own convenience.
這個人只是為了自己好 才想找你上廣播
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
I will go on the radio and tell the truth.
我打算上廣播說出真相
Ken.
研先生…
Professor.
教授
I am trying to help him,
我只是依照他想要的生活方式
no matter what he chooses in life.
努力幫助他而已
I believe his heart
我啊，比起他的身體
more than his body.
我更相信他的心
Why do you say that?
教授你…為什麼能說這種話？
Because Dr. Kentaro Fukashi chose him.
因為是深志研太郎博士選中了他
He raised you
博士會讓你誕生
because he wanted to save your heart and life,
就代表無論發生什麼事 他都想守護你的心跟生命
It had been the same after you were reborn.
就算重生，也是一樣的
He believed that your heart didn't have any harm.
他相信你的心是無害的
I respect Dr. Kentaro Fukashi.
我很尊敬深志研太郎博士
So, I believe in your heart.
所以我相信你的心
Try to get over the hardship
你的心一定可以
with your heart.
超越這些現實
Yes, I will.
是
It's Tsugaru!
是津輕！
Please stop.
請不要這樣
Please.
不…
No. Please don't take him.
不行，還是別這樣吧
Don't take him to the radio station.
別讓他上廣播
Hey!
等等
Please do as she says.
請讓她這樣做吧
Please.
拜託了
Tsugaru.
津輕小姐
What's wrong with you?
怎麼了嗎？
I'm sorry.
對不起
What?
什麼？
Please stop.
請別再這樣了
Why?
為什麼？
I don't want you
我不想
to get hurt anymore.
再看你受到傷害了
I'm sorry for being selfish.
對不起，我這樣擅作主張
But…
但是…
I don't want you to suffer anymore.
我不想再看你受折磨了
I don't care about the truth.
真相什麼的…怎麼樣都好
I can go anywhere.
我…無論是哪裡都願意去
Let's run away.
我們一起逃吧
I…
我…
I will protect you.
會守護你
I will make you smile.
我會讓你露出笑容的
I will be your radio.
我會成為你的廣播
It's time for you and I
你和我的時間…
Evolutionary theory for you and I
我和你的進化論
If you are worried about something
-有煩惱就找… -有煩惱就找天草…
-Ask Amakusa -Ask Tsugaru
找津輕
Ask Tsugaru
去問問津輕吧
Let's go back to the forest together.
我們一起回森林裡去吧
I…
我…
I will be with you forever.
會永遠跟你在一起
I promise you.
我答應你
I promise you that
我…
I will be with you forever.
會永遠跟你在一起
I promise you.
我答應你
Saki.
早紀小姐…
What?
什麼？
How?
為什麼？
How did you know that name?
你怎麼知道這名字？
It's the name…
那個人…
of my ancestor.
是我的祖先
Ah…
啊…
Tsugaru?
津輕小姐？
Tsugumi Tsugaru, 22 years old.
津輕繼實小姐，22歲
Hello, Tsugumi. Are you all right? How are you? Are you okay?
津輕小姐，還好嗎？妳還好嗎？
-It's me, your sister, Haruka. -Can you hear me?
-繼實，是姊姊啊 -聽到了嗎？
Your sister had a brain hemorrhage from here
令妹是這部位出血
because of Branch Disease.
分枝型梗塞應該就是原因
Because her brainstem
出血處在腦幹處 由於她原本就有先天血管異常
the operation is too dangerous. All we can do is to watch and wait.
動手術也很危險 現在只能觀察狀況了
It's the same as my mom.
跟家母一樣
My mom had a brain hemorrhage from the brainstem in the end,
家母最後也是腦幹部出血
soon before she died.
然後馬上就…
How is Tsugaru?
津輕小姐呢？
She is sleeping. She is not allowed to have visitors.
正在睡，無法會客
Please don't hurt her anymore.
請你…不要再摧毀繼實了
I'm begging you.
拜託你了
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
I have been living with contradictions.
我一直懷抱著矛盾
Contradictions?
矛盾？
I believed my dad
我雖然相信父親
and I also doubted him.
卻也總是很懷疑他
Huh?
什麼？
Why did he raise me?
為什麼他要創造我？
Why was I born?
我是為了什麼而生？
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
Please take care of Tsugaru.
津輕小姐就拜託你了
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I have to go.
我有地方要去
-Where? -To the forest.
-哪裡？ -森林裡
Why?
為什麼？
Please go home.
請你先回去吧
Ken.
研先生
Please come back.
請你一定要回來
Whoops.
出現了
Someone tweeted that Franken is working for Inaniwa Corporation.
有人在網路上說 怪人的工作地點是稻庭建築公司
Really?
-真的假的？ -別跟研說啊
Boss, should we leave this?
當家，放著不管好嗎？
Never mind. It's good publicity.
別在意，這是很好的宣傳啊
This is not good.
真的很不妙啊…
Hi, Seiya.
歡迎回來
-Hi.
-歡迎回來
-Thanks. -Oh that's enough. That's enough.
-夠了…
Where is Ken?
怪了，研先生呢？
We were waiting for him.
-大家都在等他 -他今天可能不會回來了
Huh?
什麼？
Tsugaru came down with sickness.
津輕小姐倒下了
-Huh? -What?
-啊？ -什麼？
KENTARO FUKASHI
（明治30年 深志研太郎）
You have mail from Ken.
研先生寄信來了，署名給你
From Ken?
研先生？
TO SEIYA
（給稻庭前輩）
FROM KEN FUKASHI
（深志研）
Dear Ken.
“稻庭前輩
I got my old memory back.
我找回以前的記憶了
From before I became a monster.
是我成為怪物前的記憶
I was in love with a lady
120年前
120 years ago.
我愛上了一位女性
Her name was Saki.
那位女性的名字叫做早紀
She was an ancestor of Tsugaru.
是津輕小姐的祖先
I killed her
變成怪物的我身上的菌
because of the bacteria as a monster.
害死了那位女性”
Excuse me. I would like to see Amakusa.
不好意思，我想見天草先生
TOKYO MUSASHI BROADCASTING
（東京武藏廣播局）
Please wait a moment.
請稍等一下
Okay.
是
I…
“我…
will tell everything on the radio.
要在廣播上說出一切
Seiya.
稻庭前輩
Please take care of Tsugaru.
津輕小姐的事就拜託你了”
Haruka.
大姐
How is Tsugaru?
津輕小姐呢？
She is still unconscious.
她還沒恢復意識
Please let her listen to Ken on the radio when you are back.
那個…要是她恢復意識了
What?
什麼？
I want to let her hear his voice.
我想讓她聽研先生的聲音
Please.
拜託了
Please sit here and wait.
那麼，請坐在這裡等待
Okay.
是
Amakusa. You know what to do, right?
天草先生，可以嗎？你明白的吧？
What?
什麼？
Don't feel empathy for him.
請別對他表示認同
Deny him if he says something strange.
要是他說什麼奇怪的事，請馬上否認
We know nothing. Okay?
因為我們什麼都不知道
Hey, I am--
-阿牛，那個… -這也是為了天草先生你
You want to keep your radio show, right?
你想繼續做廣播吧？
Okay.
我明白了
Excuse me.
不好意思
Thank you for coming.
請多指教
Hi. This is Junpei Amakusa.
好的，我是天草純平
Thank you for listening to my song.
今天節目一開頭就播放了這首歌
Let's get started.
首先我想從這個單元開始
I have a guest here in the studio.
然後，這位來賓也來到的廣播現場
Hi. I am Frankenstein.
我是科學怪人先生
PARADISE HEAVEN
（天國廣播單元）
I'm sure you know that you caused a sensation to the public.
怪人，你知道世人 正為了你的事而鬧得沸沸揚揚
Yes.
是
People think that you might have done something
這節目的主持人十勝先生
to Mr. Tokachi, a personality of this radio program.
說你對他做了一些事
I would like you to explain it today.
今天我想請問你 這件事的真相，可以嗎？
Yes.
是
First, please introduce your true self.
那麼首先，先做個真正的自我介紹吧
Okay.
我明白了
I was born in 1867
我…是1867年
in a family of poor farmers
也就是慶應三年
-in Hokuriku. -What?
-生在北陸的貧窮農家 -什麼？
There was a cholera epidemic in my village
那時我居住的村莊 有一種名叫霍亂的傳染病
and many people were killed.
死了很多人
I also lost my family
我的家人
because of that infectious disease.
也都死於這個傳染病
My true name is…
我真正的名字是…
Koroku Yamabe.
山部呼六
Let me talk about what happened
接下來我要說的 是我成為怪物之前的故事
I am Koroku Yamabe.
我叫山部呼六
Is there anything I can do?
有什麼我能幫忙的嗎？
Will you pray with me that
你願意跟我一起努力
there will be no infectious disease in the world?
讓傳染病消失嗎？
I would like to tell this to someone who is important to me.
我想告訴拼命地想在這世上 活下來的重要人們